natpe.org 2016-03-14

# NATPE | Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices of NATIONAL ASSOCIATION OF TELEVISION PROGRAM EXECUTIVES, INC. (“NATPE” or “we” or “us” or “our”) in facilitating the “Services,” as defined in the Terms of Use, on behalf of NATPE through [www.NATPE.com](https://www.natpe.com/) and other online communication tools connected thereto (together referred to as the “Site”). Our Privacy Policy applies to all visitors, members, and others who access, post, comment, purchase, or attend the Services (“Users”).

Because an essential function of the Site is performing customized matches and business searches largely based upon the information you input you allow us to use any information you provide to us for this purpose. Please read the information below to learn what types of information we are collecting and what may happen to that information you input to and through the Site. 

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. The Privacy Policy is incorporated into and made a part of our Terms of Use. Any terms we use in this Policy without defining them have the definitions given to them in the Terms of Use. As part of the Terms of Use, the Privacy Policy constitutes a legally binding agreement between you and us. By accessing, using, or receiving the Site, you agree that you have read, understand, and are bound by the terms and conditions set forth herein and you hereby consent that we will collect, use, and share your information, including your name and email address, in the ways further detailed below.

If you do not agree with any part of this Privacy Policy or our Terms of Use, please do not use, access, or receive the Services.

This means that other Users may search for, see, use, or share any of your User Content that you make available through the Service, consistent with the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use. 

**1\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

In order to better provide Users with our numerous services, we collect two types of information about our Users: Personally Identifiable Information and Nonpersonally Identifiable Information. Our primary goal in collecting information from you is to provide you with a smooth, efficient, and customized experience while using our Site.

A. _Personally Identifiable Information_ : This refers to information that lets us know the specifics of who you are. When you engage in certain activities on this site, such as creating a user account, registering for a membership, program, conference and/or exhibition, ordering a product or service, submitting content and/or posting content in discussion forums or other public areas, entering a contest or sweepstakes, filling out a survey, or sending us feedback, we may ask you to provide certain information about yourself by filling out and submitting an online form. It is completely optional for you to engage in these activities. If you elect to engage in these activities, however, we may ask that you provide us personal information, such as your first and last name, mailing address (including zip code), email address, website, employer, job title and department, telephone and facsimile numbers, and other personal identifying information. When ordering products or services or registering for a membership, program, conference or exhibition on the site, you may be asked to provide a credit card number. Depending upon the activity, some of the information we ask you to provide is identified as mandatory and some as voluntary. If you do not provide the mandatory data with respect to a particular activity, you will not be able to engage in that activity.

B. _Nonpersonally Identifiable Information_ : This refers to information that does not by itself identify a specific individual. We gather certain information about you based upon where you visit on our site in several ways. This information is compiled and analyzed on both a personal and an aggregated basis. This information may include the Web site's Uniform Resource Locator (“URL”) that you just came from, which URL you next go to, what browser you are using, and your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address. A URL is the global address of documents and other resources on the World Wide Web. An IP address is an identifier for a computer or device on a Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol (“TCP/IP”) network, such as the World Wide Web. Networks like the Web use the TCP/IP protocol to route information based on the IP address of the destination. In other words, an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the web, allowing web servers to locate and identify your computer. Computers require IP addresses in order for users to communicate on the Internet. The following are example of nonpersonally identifiable information we collect:  
i. Email open and click-throughs —We collect information about whether you have opened email messages from us and/or clicked on links in those emails. This helps us evaluate the relevance of the content in our communications.  
ii. Visits to shortcut website addresses—Some published website addresses such as are shortcuts that redirect you to a page with a longer address. When a redirect is initiated, we log shortcut website address, date, time, and IP address.  
iii. Log-ins and attempted log-ins—When you create a user account, log in, log out, or attempt to log in with invalid credentials, we record the date, time, your user ID (if you are logged in), IP address, the website address (URL) you accessed, web browser type, and a description of the event, which would include the email address you registered your account with.

**2\. Collection Methods and Use of Information**

We do not collect any Personally Identifiable Information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us. You provide certain Personally Identifiable Information to us when you: (a) register for our Services; (b) enter contests sponsored by us or one of our partners; (c) sign up for special offers from us or our Affiliates; (d) send email messages, submit forms or transmit other information through any means to us; (e) use the Site to send messages to other Users; or (f) submit your credit card or other payment information when ordering and purchasing our Services on our Site. We may also collect information from you at other points on our Site that state that such information is being collected.

In addition, we may also collect, or our third party ad server and/or content server may collect, certain Nonpersonally Identifiable Information. This information is ultimately stored in the form of store categories, and, in some cases, specific URLs. We use your IP address to diagnose problems with our servers, software, to administer our site and to gather demographic information. Our third party ad servers will also provide us with summary, but not individual, reports that will tell us how many ads were presented and clicked upon at out site.

We will primarily use your Personally Identifiable Information to provide our Services to you, as required by our agreements with you. We will also use your Personally Identifiable Information to compile lists/directories/databases of attendees/participants/speakers/members/providers/exhibitors connected to our Services, to match Users, to enhance the operation of our Site, to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, to statistically analyze use of the Site, to improve our Service offerings, and to customize our Site's content, layout, and Services. We may use Personally Identifiable Information to deliver information to you and to contact you regarding administrative notices. We may also use Personally Identifiable Information to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our agreements with you, including our Terms of Use, Copyright Dispute Policy, and this Private Policy.

**3\. Release of Information**

We do provide some of our services through contractual arrangements with our Affiliates, services providers, and other third parties. We and our Affiliates use your Personally Identifiable Information to operate our Site and to deliver Services. For example, we must release your credit card information to a card-issuing bank to confirm payment for Services purchased on this Site; release your address information to the deliverer of any service or product that you ordered; and provide order information to third parties that help us provide customer service.

We will encourage our service partners to adopt and post privacy policies. However, the use of your Personally Identifiable Information by our service partners is governed by the privacy policies of those service partners, and is not subject to our control.

Occasionally we may be required by law enforcement or judicial authorities to provide Personally Identifiable Information to the appropriate governmental authorities. We will disclose Personally Identifiable Information upon receipt of a court order, subpoena, or to cooperate with a law enforcement investigation. We fully cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our services for illegal activities. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we in good faith believe to be unlawful.

We may also provide Nonpersonally Identifiable Information about our customers' sales, traffic patterns, and related site information to third party advertisers, but these statistics do not include any Personally Identifiable Information.

**4\. Updating and Correcting Information**

We believe you should have the ability to access and edit the Personally Identifiable Information that you have provided to us. You may change any of your Personally Identifiable Information in your account online at any time by linking to your account in accordance with instructions posted elsewhere on this site. You may also access and correct your personal information and privacy preferences by writing us at:

National Association Of Television Program Executives, Inc.   
5757 Wilshire Blvd., Penthouse 10  
Los Angeles, CA 90036

Please include your name, address, and/or email address when you contact us.

We encourage you to promptly update your Personally Identifiable Information if it changes. You may ask to have the information on your account deleted or removed; however, because we keep track of past transactions, you cannot delete information associated with past transactions on this site. In addition, it may be impossible to completely delete your information without some residual information because of backups.

**5\. User Choices on Collection and Use of Information**

We may, from time to time, send you information regarding our offerings and services ( _e.g._ , account verification, changes/updates to features of the Services, technical and security notice, newsletters). In addition, we may send you offers or information from us and our partners, we may occasionally send you direct mail or email about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you. 

Only NATPE (or agents working on behalf of NATPE and under confidentiality agreements) will send you these direct mailings and emails, and only if you indicated that you do not object to these offers. Users are given the opportunity to "opt-out" of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our Site. You may opt-out from receiving specified types of communications from NATPE by clicking [here](https://www.natpe.com/account/settings). NATPE will typically only communicate with you according to your instructions. However, you may not opt out of particular Service-related communications ( _e.g._ , account verification, purchase and billing confirmations and reminders, changes/updates to features of the Services, technical and security notices).

If you do not want to receive such mailings in the first place, simply tell us when you give us your personal information at registration. Or, at any time you can easily edit your account information to no longer receive such offers and mailings. You can update your personal information on your natpe account by clicking [here](https://www.natpe.com/account). Users who are experiencing problems with updating their information should contact us at [jd@natpe.org](mailto:jd@natpe.org), and we will try to resolve your problems.

You also have choices with respect to cookies, as described below. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies some parts of our site may not work properly in your case.

**6\. Information Sharing**

We may provide your information to third parties outside NATPE (or the group of companies of which NATPE is a part) without your consent, except as noted in this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use. 

We may share your Personally Identifiable and Nonpersonally Identifiable information (including but not limited to, information from cookies, log files, location data, and usage data) with the Affiliates, or that later become part of the Affiliates. With our prior consent, Affiliates may use this information to help provide, understand, and improve the Services (including by promoting your projects) and Affiliates' own services (including by providing you with more opportunity for growth of your business). But these Affiliates will honor the choices you make about to whom they will promote your information.

**7\. Security of Information**

At our Site you can be assured that your Personally Identifiable Information is secure, consistent with current industry standards. The importance of security for all Personally Identifiable Information associated with our user is of utmost concern to us. Your Personally Identifiable Information is protected in several ways. Access by you to your Personally Identifiable Information is available through a password and unique user ID selected by you. This password is encrypted. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. In addition, your Personally Identifiable Information resides on a secure server that only selected NATPE personnel and contractors have access to via password. We encrypt your Personally Identifiable Information and thereby prevent unauthorized parties from viewing such information when it is transmitted to us.

Personal information that you provide that is not Personally Identifiable Information also resides on a secure server and is only accessible via password. Since this information is not accessible from outside NATPE you will not be asked to select a password in order to view or modify such information.

In order to most efficiently serve you, credit card transactions and order fulfillment are handled by established third party banking, processing agents, distribution institutions. They receive the information needed to verify and authorize your credit card or other payment information and to process and ship your order. In order to best promote your businesses and projects, customer list rentals are handled by established third party fulfillment houses. They receive the information about you and your business/projects needed to best promote your business/projects to the individuals and companies on our customer lists.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your Personally Identifiable Information, you acknowledge that: (a) there are security and privacy limitations of the Internet which are beyond our control; (b) the security, integrity and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through this site cannot be guaranteed; and (c) any such information and data may be viewed or tampered with in transit by a third party.

**8\. Cookies**

When you use our Site we will store cookies on your computer in order to facilitate and customize your use of our site. A cookie is a small data text file, which a Web site stores on your computer's hard drive (if your Web browser permits) that can later be retrieved to identify you to us. Our cookies store randomly assigned user identification numbers, the country where you are located, and your first name to welcome you back to our site. The cookies make your use of the site easier, make the site run more smoothly and help us to maintain a secure site. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, but some parts of our site may not work properly in that case.

We may use an outside ad serving company to display banner advertisements on our site. As part of their service, they will place a separate cookie on your computer. We will not provide any third-party ad server with any of your Personally Identifiable Information or information about your purchases. We and our third party ad server will collect and use Nonpersonally Identifiable Information about you, such as your IP address, browser type, the server your computer is logged onto, the area code and zip code associated with your server and whether you responded to a particular ad. Other advertisers may also place banner ads on our site in the same manner as above, but we will not disclose any Personally Identifiable Information to them.

**9\. Changes To Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to change this **Privacy Policy** at any time. Such changes, modifications, additions or deletions shall be effective immediately upon notice thereof, which may be given by means including, but not limited to issuing an email to the email address listed by registered Users and posting the revised Policy on [www.NATPE.com](https://www.natpe.com/). You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to maintain a valid email address as a registered user, review this site and this Policy periodically and to be aware of any modifications. Your continued use of the Site after such modifications will constitute your: (a) acknowledgment of the modified Policy; and (b) agreement to abide and be bound by the modified Policy.

**10\. Privacy Policies of Third Party Sites**

Except as otherwise discussed in this Privacy Policy, this document only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. Other sites accessible through our site have their own privacy policies and data collection, use and disclosure practices. Please consult each site's privacy policy. We are not responsible for the policies or practices of third parties. Additionally, other companies which place advertising on our site may collect information about you when you view or click on their advertising through the use of cookies. We cannot control this collection of information. You should contact these advertisers directly if you have any questions about their use of the information that they collect.  
**  
11\. Miscellaneous Privacy Issues**

You must be at least 18 years old to use this site. As noted in the Terms of Use, our policy is that we do not knowingly collect, use or disclose Personally Identifiable Information about visitors that are under 13 years of age. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register for the Services or send any personal information about yourself to us. If we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a child under 13 may have provided us personal information, please contact us at [jd@natpe.org](mailto:jd@natpe.org).

You should also be aware that when Personally Identifiable Information is voluntarily disclosed (i.e. your name, email address, etc.) in the forums, blogs, or other public areas on this Site, that information, along with any information disclosed in your communication, can be collected and used by third parties and may result in unsolicited messages from third parties. Such activities are beyond our control and this Policy does not apply to such information. Any submissions to chat rooms, blog, forums or other public areas on this Site are accepted with the understanding that they are accessible to all third parties. If you do not want your comments to be viewed by third parties, you are advised not to make any submissions. Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your password and/or account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you are online.

**12\. Questions**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us by sending a letter to:

National Association Of Television Program Executives, Inc.   
Attn: Privacy Compliance Officer  
5757 Wilshire Blvd., Penthouse 10  
Los Angeles, CA 90036

You may also contact us by email at [jd@natpe.org](mailto:jd@natpe.org)
